[
    [
        {
            "question": "In this type of government, citizens collectively make decisions by voting directly on potential laws and policies. One of the earliest examples existed in ancient Athens.",
            "answers": ["Direct Democracy"],
            "category": "History",
            "id": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "A pioneer of Renaissance polyphony, this Flemish composer's works include predominantly sacred music like motets and masses. He's known for the complexity and expressiveness of his vocal pieces.",
            "answers": ["Josquin des Prez"],
            "category": "Music",
            "id": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "His dialogues explore themes of justice, the ideal society, and the nature of knowledge. A student of Socrates, his most famous student would go on to teach Alexander the Great. This thinker founded the Academy in Athens.",
            "answers": ["Plato"],
            "category": "Philosophy",
            "id": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "These chordates possess a notochord during development, along with gill slits and a hollow dorsal nerve cord. The group includes all mammals, birds, fish, and more.",
            "answers": ["Vertebrates"],
            "category": "Biology",
            "id": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "These microscopic infectious agents have a simple structure and are capable of infecting all forms of life. To reproduce, they hijack the machinery of a host cell. ",
            "answers": ["Viruses"],
            "category": "Biology",
            "id": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "What company started a search engine project called \"A9\" to compete with Google and has a profitable cloud computing product while also being known for online shopping?",
            "answers": ["Amazon"],
            "category": "Business",
            "Difficulty": "Easy",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 5
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, this hero known for his immense strength was given 12 almost impossible tasks to complete. He is also the inspiration for a 1997 Disney animated film.",
            "answers": ["Hercules"],
            "category": "",
            "Difficulty": "",
            "Fact Checked": "No",
            "id": 6
        },
        {
            "question": "In this Shakespeare play, a Scottish nobleman spurred by the prophecies of three witches murders his king to attain the throne. Plagued by guilt and fear, he becomes increasingly tyrannical.",
            "answers": ["Macbeth"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "id": 7
        },
        {
            "question": "Derived from a Greek word for 'love of wisdom,' this intellectual pursuit uses reason to explore ideas about existence, morality, knowledge, and values.",
            "answers": ["Philosophy"],
            "category": "Philosophy",
            "id": 8
        },
        {
            "question": "Often painted in bold color combinations, this Dutch Post-Impressionist had a troubled life yet went on to become one of the most celebrated artists posthumously. Some of his best-known works include 'Starry Night' and his self-portraits.",
            "answers": ["Vincent van Gogh", "van Gogh"],
            "category": "Art",
            "id": 9
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question": "Found throughout the ocean, this phylum of marine invertebrates is characterized by radial symmetry, soft bodies, and tentacles armed with stinging cells.  Some form mutually beneficial relationships with clownfish.",
            "answers": [
                "Cnidaria (Jellyfish, corals, sea anemones)",
                "Cnidaria"
            ],
            "category": "Biology",
            "id": 10
        },
        {
            "question": "Which NFL wide receiver who played 20 seasons, played his last game for the Seattle Seahawks, but won three superbowls with the San Francisco 49ers holds the NFL records for most total touchdowns?",
            "answers": ["Jerry Rice"],
            "category": "Sports",
            "Difficulty": "Easy",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 11
        },
        {
            "question": "This creature's riddle appears in Sophocles's play *Oedipus Rex*. She has the wings of an eagle, the body of a lion, and the head of a woman. In Greek myth, she devours those who fail to answer her question correctly.",
            "answers": ["Sphinx"],
            "category": "Mythology",
            "id": 12
        },
        {
            "question": "This Italian explorer's voyages across the Atlantic helped pave the way for subsequent European colonialism in the Americas, though he did not reach the continental mainland.",
            "answers": ["Christopher Columbus", "Columbus"],
            "category": "History",
            "id": 13
        },
        {
            "question": "This chemical element is highly reactive and the primary component of table salt. It has the symbol 'Na' and a silvery-white metallic appearance in its pure form.",
            "answers": ["Sodium"],
            "category": "Chemistry",
            "id": 14
        },
        {
            "question": "This conflict pitted the Union and Confederacy against each other, dividing the nation as they battled over issues including states' rights and the enslavement of people.",
            "answers": ["American Civil War", "Civil War"],
            "category": "History",
            "id": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek religion, he was the god of war known for his violence and bloodshed. Identified with Mars in Roman mythology, he was an unpopular figure amongst many of the other gods of Olympus.",
            "answers": ["Ares"],
            "category": "Mythology",
            "id": 16
        },
        {
            "question": "This fictional character, introduced in a novel published in 1937, was raised by his uncle after the tragic death of his parents. Known for his small stature and hairy feet, he embarks on an epic journey to destroy a powerful artifact that threatens the fate of his world.",
            "answers": ["Frodo Baggins", "Frodo"],
            "category": "",
            "Difficulty": "",
            "Fact Checked": "",
            "id": 17
        },
        {
            "question": "This term often refers to the era from the fall of the Western Roman Empire to the Renaissance. Marked by feudalism and warfare, it's sometimes referred to as the 'Dark Ages,' though that label is debated.",
            "answers": ["Middle Ages"],
            "category": "History",
            "id": 18
        },
        {
            "question": "Sharing a border with the Atacama Desert, the Pacific Ocean, and the Andes Mountains, this country features diverse terrain including a long coastline and the southernmost city in the world.",
            "answers": ["Chile"],
            "category": "Geography",
            "id": 19
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question": "A Renaissance-era mathematician and astronomer from the Polish city of Thorn, this scholar challenged the long-held belief that the Earth was the center of the universe. His revolutionary work 'De revolutionibus orbium coelestium' proposed a heliocentric model, with the Sun at the center and the planets, including Earth, revolving around it. This theory, which contradicted the geocentric model of Ptolemy, laid the foundation for modern astronomy and is considered a key event in the Scientific Revolution.",
            "answers": ["Nicolaus Copernicus", "Copernicus"],
            "category": "History",
            "id": 20
        },
        {
            "question": "Designed by French sculptor Frédéric Auguste Bartholdi, this towering neoclassical sculpture of a Roman goddess was originally made of copper sheets assembled on a framework of steel and concrete. It has a distinctive green patina color and was a gift from France to the United States. This iconic statue depicts a robed female figure holding a torch aloft and stands in New York Harbor.",
            "answers": [
                "The Statue of Liberty",
                "Statue of Liberty",
                "Libertas"
            ],
            "category": "Landmarks",
            "id": 21
        },
        {
            "question": "A celebrated English novelist of the early 19th century, she is best known for her witty social satires that explored the societal norms and rigid class structures of Georgian-era Britain. Her most famous work, published anonymously in 1813, centers on the spirited Elizabeth Bennet and her confrontations with the haughty Mr. Darcy, ultimately leading to a romance that defies class prejudices.",
            "answers": ["Jane Austen", "Austen"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 22
        },
        {
            "question": "Founded in 1867 as a small agricultural village in the Salt River Valley, this city was incorporated in 1881 and named after the mythical bird that cyclically regenerates from its own ashes. Known for its hot desert climate, it is now the largest state capital in the United States by population.",
            "answers": ["Phoenix"],
            "category": "Geography",
            "Difficulty": "Easy",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 23
        },
        {
            "question": "The only mammals capable of true, sustained flight, these nocturnal creatures possess an advanced biological sonar system that allows them to navigate and hunt in complete darkness. While most species feed on insects, some larger varieties consume fruits, nectar, or even the blood of other animals.",
            "answers": ["Bats", "Bat"],
            "category": "Biology",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 24
        },
        {
            "question": "A vital transition metal found in trace amounts throughout the human body, it is the main component of hemoglobin, the protein in red blood cells responsible for transporting oxygen. With an atomic number of 26, this element's chemical symbol is derived from the Latin word 'ferrum,' meaning iron-bearing or iron-producing.",
            "answers": ["Iron", "Fe"],
            "category": "Chemistry",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 25
        },
        {
            "question": "A Chinese philosopher who lived during the Warring States Period (475-221 BCE), he emphasized social harmony, respect for tradition, and the importance of a ruler's virtuous example in governing. His teachings, compiled in the Analects, formed the basis of the philosophical system known as Confucianism, which profoundly influenced East Asian societies.",
            "answers": ["Confucius", "Kong Qiu"],
            "category": "Philosophy",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 26
        },
        {
            "question": "The SI unit for electric current is named after this French physicist and mathematician, who formulated the fundamental relationship between electric current and magnetic fields in conductors. While not the primary inventor, he made significant contributions to the development of the telegraph. The unit represents the flow of one coulomb of charge per second.",
            "answers": ["Andre-Marie Ampere", "Ampere", "Amp"],
            "category": "Physics",
            "Difficulty": "Hard",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 27
        },
        {
            "question": "Situated between Europe and Asia, this vast inland body of water has an area approximately the size of Japan and is often referred to as the world's largest lake, even though it has 'sea' in its name. With no outflows and a high salinity level, it is technically classified as a salt lake.",
            "answers": ["Caspian Sea"],
            "category": "Geography",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 28
        },
        {
            "question": "The last Roman emperor of the Julio-Claudian dynasty, this notorious ruler was infamous for his cruelty, extravagance, and rumored to have played the lyre while Rome burned during the Great Fire of 64 CE. He persecuted early Christians and faced multiple rebellions during his reign, which ended with his suicide in 68 CE.",
            "answers": ["Nero", "Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus"],
            "category": "History",
            "Difficulty": "Hard",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 29
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question": "Named after an Italian mathematician from Pisa, this numerical sequence, starting with 0 and 1, follows a simple pattern where each subsequent number is the sum of the two preceding ones (0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13...). This recursive sequence has been observed in nature, art, and even the architecture of spiral galaxies.",
            "answers": [
                "The Fibonacci Sequence",
                "Fibonacci Sequence",
                "Fibonacci"
            ],
            "category": "Mathematics",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 30
        },
        {
            "question": "A prolific Austrian composer of the Classical era, this child prodigy began composing music at the age of five. He is renowned for his operas, such as 'The Marriage of Figaro,' 'Don Giovanni,' and 'Così fan tutte,' as well as his symphonies, concertos, and chamber works, which showcased his exceptional melodic and harmonic gifts.",
            "answers": ["Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart", "Amadeus Mozart", "Mozart"],
            "category": "Music",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 31
        },
        {
            "question": "This American novelist, known for her exploration of racial injustice and societal norms in the American South, gained widespread acclaim for her Pulitzer Prize-winning novel 'To Kill a Mockingbird.' Years later, she published 'Go Set a Watchman,' which was originally written as an early draft of her famous work.",
            "answers": ["Harper Lee", "Lee"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 32
        },
        {
            "question": "Serving as the administrative capital of the European Union, this cosmopolitan city is home to the Grand Place, a stunning medieval square recognized as a UNESCO World Heritage Site. Known for its diverse architecture, cuisine, and vibrant cultural scene, it is also the headquarters of the European Commission and other EU institutions.",
            "answers": ["Brussels"],
            "category": "Geography",
            "Difficulty": "Easy",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 33
        },
        {
            "question": "Built as a magnificent tomb for the Fourth Dynasty pharaoh Khufu, this iconic ancient Egyptian monument stands at a towering height of 481 feet and is the oldest and largest of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World. Its massive scale and precise construction have baffled architects and historians for centuries.",
            "answers": [
                "The Great Pyramid of Giza",
                "Great Pyramid of Giza",
                "Pyramid of Giza"
            ],
            "category": "History",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 34
        },
        {
            "question": "This influential Greek philosopher, who lived in Athens during the 5th century BCE, is considered one of the founders of Western philosophy. He is renowned for his contributions to ethics, epistemology, and metaphysics, as well as his use of a question-and-answer approach to stimulate critical thinking and challenge assumptions.",
            "answers": ["Socrates"],
            "category": "Philosophy",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 35
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the oldest and most widely practiced religions, this monotheistic faith traces its origins to the biblical figure of Abraham and emphasizes the importance of a covenant between God and the Jewish people. Its sacred texts, including the Torah and the Talmud, have shaped Jewish traditions, laws, and culture.",
            "answers": ["Judaism"],
            "category": "Religion",
            "Difficulty": "Easy",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 36
        },
        {
            "question": "Located just below the Arctic Circle, this island nation is known for its stunning landscapes, including glaciers, volcanoes, and geothermic hot springs. Its capital city, Reykjavik, is the world's northernmost capital and is home to many cultural institutions that preserve the country's rich Norse heritage and mythological sagas.",
            "answers": ["Iceland"],
            "category": "Geography",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 37
        },
        {
            "question": "Endothermic vertebrates that evolved from feathered theropod dinosaurs, these creatures are distinguished by their toothless beaks adapted for diverse diets and their ability to fly, though some members of this group have lost that capacity over time. Their warm-blooded nature and feathered bodies set them apart from reptiles.",
            "answers": ["Birds", "Aves"],
            "category": "Biology",
            "Difficulty": "Hard",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 38
        },
        {
            "question": "Written in iambic pentameter, this tragic play by William Shakespeare tells the story of two star-crossed lovers from feuding families in Verona, Italy. Their forbidden love ultimately leads to their untimely deaths, cementing the play's reputation as one of the most famous and widely studied works in English literature.",
            "answers": ["Romeo and Juliet"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 39
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question": "Often found in deserts, these reptiles are equipped with scales, lay eggs, and regulate their body temperature by seeking sunlight or shade. Some species change color or have venomous bites.",
            "answers": ["Lizards"],
            "category": "Biology",
            "id": 40
        },
        {
            "question": "Though short-lived as an entity, this alliance included major powers like Britain, France, and Russia and ultimately opposed the Central Powers during World War I.",
            "answers": ["Triple Entente"],
            "category": "History",
            "id": 41
        },
        {
            "question": "The periodic table arranges them according to atomic number and groups them by shared properties. Some examples include carbon, iron, and gold.",
            "answers": ["Elements"],
            "category": "Chemistry",
            "id": 42
        },
        {
            "question": "This American writer depicted the hardships faced by migrant workers during the Great Depression in his novels \"The Grapes of Wrath\" and \"Of Mice and Men.",
            "answers": ["John Steinbeck", "Steinbeck"],
            "category": "",
            "Difficulty": "",
            "Fact Checked": "No",
            "id": 43
        },
        {
            "question": "With the world's longest coastline and most islands, this archipelago nation in Southeast Asia experiences tropical monsoons, earthquakes, and volcanic eruptions due to its position on the 'Ring of Fire'.",
            "answers": ["Indonesia"],
            "category": "Geography",
            "id": 44
        },
        {
            "question": "While this Italian Renaissance sculptor created several iconic pieces, perhaps his most famous is a 17-foot statue depicting a biblical hero famed for defeating a giant.",
            "answers": ["Michelangelo"],
            "category": "Art",
            "id": 45
        },
        {
            "question": "This celestial body, which appears red in the night sky due to iron oxide, has a thin atmosphere and is home to the largest volcano in the solar system, Olympus Mons.",
            "answers": ["Mars"],
            "category": "",
            "Difficulty": "",
            "Fact Checked": "No",
            "id": 46
        },
        {
            "question": "A pioneer in the development of psychoanalysis, this Austrian neurologist proposed that the unconscious mind drives behaviors. His concepts such as the id, ego, and superego gained widespread influence.",
            "answers": ["Sigmund Freud", "Freud"],
            "category": "Psychology",
            "id": 47
        },
        {
            "question": "He proposed the theory of special relativity, revolutionizing our understanding of space and time. His famous equation E=mc\u00b2 reveals the relationship between energy and mass.",
            "answers": ["Albert Einstein", "Einstein"],
            "category": "Science",
            "id": 48
        },
        {
            "question": "Found primarily in Africa, this is the largest living land animal and boasts a prehensile trunk used for drinking, grasping, and communication. The adults have large tusks made of ivory.",
            "answers": ["Elephant"],
            "category": "Biology",
            "id": 49
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question": "An archetypal Renaissance man, this Italian polymath conceptualized designs centuries ahead of their time, including plans for a helicopter and concentrated solar power. His genius spanned art, science, invention, and more, but he is most renowned for paintings like the Mona Lisa.",
            "answers": ["Leonardo da Vinci", "da Vinci"],
            "category": "Renaissance",
            "id": 50
        },
        {
            "question": "Flowing through Central and Western Europe, this major river has served as an important commercial transportation route for centuries. While its source is in the Swiss Alps, it travels over 800 miles and forms much of the border between France and Germany before emptying into the North Sea, with historic castles and vineyards dotting its scenic banks.",
            "answers": ["Rhine River", "Rhine"],
            "category": "Geography",
            "id": 51
        },
        {
            "question": "A member of the columbidae family, these predominantly white birds have been known for their ability to find their way home from great distance. These birds are symbolic of peace across many cultures and lend their name to a popular brand of soap.",
            "answers": ["Dove"],
            "category": "Biology",
            "id": 52
        },
        {
            "question": "This prolific 20th century Spanish artist spent much of his adult life in Paris. He experimented across mediums like sculpture and printmaking, and his early works featured somber figures and blue tones, while African masks influenced his later distinctive fragmented style. He is best known for renowned for co-founding the Cubist movement.",
            "answers": ["Pablo Picasso", "Picasso"],
            "category": "Art",
            "id": 53
        },
        {
            "question": "The heaviest US president at over 300 pounds, this leader emphasized economic influence over military might in foreign policy. After his presidency, he became the only person to also serve as Chief Justice of the Supreme Court, heading both executive and judicial branches. An oft-told anecdote involves him getting stuck in a White House bathtub.",
            "answers": ["William Howard Taft", "William Taft", "Taft"],
            "category": "U.S. Presidents",
            "id": 54
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the most influential composers of the 20th century, his neoclassical period saw a return to 18th century styles and forms. His early works exhibited classical structures before his iconoclastic ballets like 'The Rite of Spring' sparked a riot at their premiere in Paris.",
            "answers": ["Igor Stravinsky", "Stravinsky"],
            "category": "Music",
            "id": 55
        },
        {
            "question": "Which beloved children's book character, who first appeared in a 1900 book by A.A. Milne, lives in the Hundred Acre Wood and has friends like Piglet, Tigger, and Eeyore? This honey-loving bear with a distinct yellow fur color has been featured in numerous films, television shows, and merchandise.",
            "answers": ["Winnie the Pooh"],
            "category": "Children's Literature",
            "id": 74
        },
        {
            "question": "A landlocked country in South Asia, its territory contains ancient Buddhist monasteries and diverse wildlife. But it is best known for its dramatic Himalayan mountain landscapes, including the world's tallest peak, Mount Everest.",
            "answers": ["Nepal"],
            "category": "Geography",
            "id": 57
        },
        {
            "question": "Based on an E.T.A. Hoffmann fairy tale, this beloved Christmas ballet composed by Tchaikovsky features characters like the Mouse King and Sugar Plum Fairy fending off the evil Mouse Queen.",
            "answers": ["The Nutcracker", "Nutcracker"],
            "category": "Fine Arts",
            "Difficulty": "Easy",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 58
        },
        {
            "question": "A fundamental shape in Euclidean geometry, squares are a subset of these shapes. They feature four right angles and opposite sides that are parallel and equal in length.",
            "answers": ["Rectangle"],
            "category": "Mathematics",
            "id": 59
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question": "This planet has over 80 known moons. Though smaller than Jupiter, it is still larger in diameter than any dwarf planet, with a mostly nitrogen atmosphere and methane lakes on its surface. It is the sixth planet from the sun and has a distinctive system of rings.",
            "answers": ["Saturn"],
            "category": "Astronomy",
            "id": 60
        },
        {
            "question": "This is an epic poem from early English literature, though its setting is in Scandinavia. It is likely over 1000 years old and the one copy is in the Nowell Codex. It features alliterative verse and following a hero's battles against monstrous creatures.",
            "answers": ["Beowulf"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "id": 61
        },
        {
            "question": "A 19th century American poet who celebrated individuality and democracy in free verse, his groundbreaking major work titled after himself found both widespread critical acclaim and controversy.",
            "answers": ["Walt Whitman", "Whitman"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "id": 62
        },
        {
            "question": "Previously known as Edo, this Asian capital is the largest and most populous metropolitan area worldwide. It is home to the Imperial Palace, the official residence of the Emperor of Japan.",
            "answers": ["Tokyo"],
            "category": "Geography",
            "Difficulty": "Easy",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 63
        },
        {
            "question": "This classic Gothic novel, first published anonymously in 1818, is subtitled 'The Modern Prometheus' and narrated in part by a man sailing to explore the North Pole. It was written by Mary Shelley.",
            "answers": ["Frankenstein"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "Difficulty": "Easy",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 64
        },
        {
            "question": "Derived from Latin meaning 'middle voice', this verb form indicates the subject acts upon itself, like in the example 'The door opened' where the door is not actively doing the opening.",
            "answers": ["Middle Voice"],
            "category": "Language",
            "id": 65
        },
        {
            "question": "Described as an intense period of heightened creativity and productivity, this psychological state is sometimes linked to mental illness, though not everyone who experiences it has an underlying disorder.",
            "answers": ["Mania"],
            "category": "Psychology",
            "id": 66
        },
        {
            "question": "A founder of French Impressionist painting, he is renowned for his landscape scenes depicting the Japanese bridge in his garden at Giverny as well as his iconic water lily series experimenting with light and color.",
            "answers": ["Claude Monet", "Monet"],
            "category": "Art",
            "id": 67
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the most famous Hollywood actresses of her era, she was renowned for her beauty, multiple marriages, and philanthropy. She became the first celebrity to be paid $1 million for a single film role.",
            "answers": ["Elizabeth Taylor", "Taylor"],
            "category": "Film",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 68
        },
        {
            "question": "A leading Post-Impressionist painter from the Netherlands, he was known for his distinctive style featuring swirling brushwork and bold colors, exemplified in his famous sunflower series. A renowned anecdote involves him severing his own ear.",
            "answers": ["Vincent van Gogh", "van Gogh"],
            "category": "Art",
            "Difficulty": "Medium",
            "Fact Checked": "Yes",
            "id": 69
        }
    ],
    [
        {
            "question": "Though primarily prose, this work from the Romantic era features interludes of poetry and tells a tale of doomed love and revenge. It's set against the bleak Yorkshire moors and features the characters of Heathcliff and Catherine.",
            "answers": ["Wuthering Heights"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "id": 70
        },
        {
            "question": "Which American author, who wrote the novel 'The Human Stain' and the short story 'Everyman,' won the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction in 1998 for his book about the life of a retired professor?",
            "answers": ["Philip Roth", "Roth"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "id": 71
        },
        {
            "question": "Which renowned British artist, who pioneered the abstract art movement in the early 20th century, is known for his distinctive canvases featuring geometric shapes and bold colors? This artist, who co-founded the Vorticist movement, produced works like 'Composition with Red Blue and Yellow' and 'Black on Maroon.'",
            "answers": ["Piet Mondrian", "Mondrian"],
            "category": "Art",
            "id": 72
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ancient Greek philosopher, who was a student of Socrates and a teacher of Aristotle, founded the Academy in Athens? This philosopher, who wrote dialogues such as 'The Republic' and 'Symposium,' is considered one of the most influential thinkers in Western philosophy.",
            "answers": ["Plato"],
            "category": "Philosophy",
            "id": 73
        },
        {
            "question": "An acclaimed Baroque composer whose early training focused on the harpsichord, he composed an extensive range of instrumental works in addition to his renowned choral pieces while residing in Leipzig, including the monumental 'St. Matthew Passion.'",
            "answers": ["Johann Sebastian Bach", "Bach"],
            "category": "Music",
            "id": 74
        },
        {
            "question": "Which British rock band, formed in London in the 1960s, is known for their iconic album covers, progressive rock sound, and concept albums like 'The Wall' and 'The Dark Side of the Moon'? This band, whose founding members included Roger Waters, David Gilmour, and Nick Mason, has sold over 250 million records worldwide.",
            "answers": ["Pink Floyd"],
            "category": "Music",
            "id": 75
        },
        {
            "question": "This American inventor, who held over 1,000 patents, is best known for developing the first practical incandescent light bulb and establishing the first electric power distribution system. He also founded a prominent research laboratory in New Jersey.",
            "answers": ["Thomas Edison", "Edison"],
            "category": "Inventors",
            "id": 76
        },
        {
            "question": "This Russian novelist and playwright, who lived from 1828 to 1910, is considered one of the greatest writers of all time. Some of his most famous works include 'Crime and Punishment,' 'The Brothers Karamazov,' and 'Notes from Underground.'",
            "answers": ["Fyodor Dostoevsky", "Dostoevsky"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "id": 77
        },
        {
            "question": "This French artist, who lived from 1834 to 1917, is renowned for his Impressionist paintings, which often depicted scenes of modern Parisian life. His most famous works include 'Luncheon on the Grass' and 'Olympia.'",
            "answers": ["Édouard Manet", "Manet"],
            "category": "Art",
            "id": 78
        },
        {
            "question": "This American author, who lived from 1919 to 1984, is best known for writing the classic novels 'The Catcher in the Rye' and 'Franny and Zooey.' He was a reclusive figure who avoided public attention for much of his life.",
            "answers": ["J.D. Salinger", "Salinger"],
            "category": "Literature",
            "id": 79
        }
    ]
]
